<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="class.xsl"?>

<book>
  <info>
    <name>ColourFX</name>
    <type>class</type>
    <module>Vector</module>
    <comment>Support for applying colour transformation effects.</comment>
    <version>1</version>
    <id>3db0d377</id>
    <idstring>ID_COLOURFX</idstring>
    <category>Graphics</category>
    <include>modules/colourfx.h</include>
    <copyright>Paul Manias © 2010-2024</copyright>
    <description>
<p>Use ColourFX to perform colour transformations on an input source.  A <field>Mode</field> must be selected and any required <field>Values</field> defined prior to rendering.</p>
<p>SVG requires that the calculations are performed on non-premultiplied colour values.  If the input graphics consists of premultiplied colour values, those values are automatically converted into non-premultiplied colour values for this operation.</p></description>
    <source>
      <file path="filters/">filter_colourmatrix.cpp</file>
    </source>
  </info>

  <actions>
    <action>
      <name>Draw</name>
      <comment>Render the effect to the target bitmap.</comment>
    </action>

  </actions>

  <fields>
    <field>
      <name>Mode</name>
      <comment>Defines the algorithm that will process the input source.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type lookup="CM">INT</type>
      <description>
<types lookup="CM"/>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Values</name>
      <comment>A list of input values for the algorithm defined by <field>Mode</field>.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE []</type>
      <description>
<p>The meaning of the input values is dependent on the selected <field>Mode</field>.  Each mode documents the total number of values that must be defined for them to work properly.</p>
<p>When values are not defined, they default to 0.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>XMLDef</name>
      <comment>Returns an SVG compliant XML string that describes the effect.</comment>
      <access read="G">Get</access>
      <type>STRING</type>
    </field>

  </fields>
  <types>
    <constants lookup="CM" comment="Colour modes for ColourFX.">
      <const name="BRIGHTNESS">Adjust brightness using the first parameter to define the intensity.</const>
      <const name="COLOURISE">Colourise the input with the first 3 parameters used as RGB multipliers and the fourth parameter controlling intensity from 0 - 1.0.</const>
      <const name="CONTRAST">Adjust contrast using the first parameter to define the intensity from -1.0 to 1.0.</const>
      <const name="DESATURATE">Desaturate the input completely so that it is rendered in greyscale.</const>
      <const name="HUE">Adjust the hue by 0 - 360 degrees using the first parameter.</const>
      <const name="HUE_ROTATE">Rotate the hue by 0 - 360 degrees, controlled by the first parameter.</const>
      <const name="LUMINANCE_ALPHA">Converts each RGB value to greyscale, which then overrides the alpha channel.</const>
      <const name="MATRIX">Process the supplied 5x4 matrix values.</const>
      <const name="NONE">Do nothing.</const>
      <const name="SATURATE">Adjust colour saturation with the first parameter defining the multiplier.</const>
    </constants>

  </types>
  <structs>
  </structs>
</book>
