<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="class.xsl"?>

<book>
  <info>
    <name>SourceFX</name>
    <type>class</type>
    <module>Vector</module>
    <comment>Renders a source vector in the effect pipeline.</comment>
    <version>1</version>
    <id>16f8c294</id>
    <idstring>SOURCEFX</idstring>
    <category>Graphics</category>
    <copyright>Paul Manias © 2010-2025</copyright>
    <description>
<p>The SourceFX class will render a named vector into a given rectangle within the current user coordinate system.</p>
<p>Technically the SourceFX object is represented by a new viewport, the bounds of which are defined by attributes <code>X</code>, <code>Y</code>, <code>Width</code> and <code>Height</code>.  The placement and scaling of the referenced vector is controlled by the <fl>AspectRatio</fl> field.</p></description>
    <source>
      <file path="filters/">filter_source.cpp</file>
    </source>
  </info>

  <actions>
    <action>
      <name>Draw</name>
      <comment>Render the source vector to the target bitmap.</comment>
      <prototype>ERR acDraw(*Object, DOUBLE X, DOUBLE Y, DOUBLE Width, DOUBLE Height)</prototype>
      <input>
        <param type="LONG" name="X">The X position of the region to be drawn.</param>
        <param type="LONG" name="Y">The Y position of the region to be drawn.</param>
        <param type="LONG" name="Width">The width of the region to be drawn.</param>
        <param type="LONG" name="Height">The height of the region to be drawn.</param>
      </input>
    </action>

  </actions>

  <fields>
    <field>
      <name>AspectRatio</name>
      <comment>SVG compliant aspect ratio settings.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type lookup="ARF">INT</type>
      <description>
<types lookup="ARF"/>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Source</name>
      <comment>The source <class name="Vector">Vector</class> that will be rendered.</comment>
      <access read="R" write="S">Read/Set</access>
      <type>OBJECTPTR</type>
      <description>
<p>The Source field must refer to a <class name="Vector">Vector</class> that will be rendered in the filter pipeline.  The vector must be under the ownership of the same <class name="VectorScene">VectorScene</class> that the filter pipeline belongs.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>SourceName</name>
      <comment>Name of a source definition to be rendered.</comment>
      <access write="S">Set</access>
      <type>STRING</type>
      <description>
<p>Setting Def to the name of a pre-registered scene definition will reference that object in <fl>Source</fl>.  If the name is not registered then <code>ERR::Search</code> is returned.  The named object must be derived from the <class name="Vector">Vector</class> class.</p>
<p>Vectors are registered via the <class name="VectorScene" method="AddDef">VectorScene.AddDef()</class> method.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>XMLDef</name>
      <comment>Returns an SVG compliant XML string that describes the filter.</comment>
      <access read="G">Get</access>
      <type>STRING</type>
    </field>

  </fields>
  <types>
    <constants lookup="ARF" comment="Aspect ratios control alignment, scaling and clipping.">
      <const name="MEET">Aspect ratio is preserved. The entire viewbox will be visible in the viewport.  The viewbox is scaled up as much as possible.</const>
      <const name="NONE">Scale the viewbox to match the size of the viewport.  Aspect ratio is not preserved.</const>
      <const name="SLICE">Aspect ratio is preserved. The viewbox can extend beyond the viewport's edges on one axis.  The viewbox is scaled up as much as possible.</const>
      <const name="X_MAX">Align to the right.</const>
      <const name="X_MID">Align to the horizontal center.</const>
      <const name="X_MIN">Align to the left.</const>
      <const name="Y_MAX">Align to the bottom.</const>
      <const name="Y_MID">Align to the vertical center.</const>
      <const name="Y_MIN">Align to the top.</const>
    </constants>

  </types>
  <structs>
  </structs>
</book>
