<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="class.xsl"?>

<book>
  <info>
    <name>VectorRectangle</name>
    <type>class</type>
    <module>Vector</module>
    <comment>Extends the Vector class with support for generating rectangles.</comment>
    <version>1</version>
    <id>ac2f506d</id>
    <idstring>ID_VECTORRECTANGLE</idstring>
    <category>Graphics</category>
    <include>modules/vectorrectangle.h</include>
    <copyright>Paul Manias © 2010-2023</copyright>
    <description>
<p>VectorRectangle extends the <class name="Vector">Vector</class> class with the ability to generate rectangular paths.</p></description>
    <source>
      <file path="vectors/">rectangle.cpp</file>
    </source>
  </info>

  <fields>
    <field>
      <name>Dimensions</name>
      <comment>Dimension flags define whether individual dimension fields contain fixed or relative values.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>INT</type>
      <description>
<p>The following dimension flags are supported:</p>
<types lookup="DMF">
<type name="FIXED_HEIGHT">The <field>Height</field> value is a fixed coordinate.</type>
<type name="FIXED_WIDTH">The <field>Width</field> value is a fixed coordinate.</type>
<type name="FIXED_X">The <field>X</field> value is a fixed coordinate.</type>
<type name="FIXED_Y">The <field>Y</field> value is a fixed coordinate.</type>
<type name="FIXED_RADIUS_X">The <field>RoundX</field> value is a fixed coordinate.</type>
<type name="FIXED_RADIUS_Y">The <field>RoundY</field> value is a fixed coordinate.</type>
<type name="RELATIVE_HEIGHT">The <field>Height</field> value is a relative coordinate.</type>
<type name="RELATIVE_WIDTH">The <field>Width</field> value is a relative coordinate.</type>
<type name="RELATIVE_X">The <field>X</field> value is a relative coordinate.</type>
<type name="RELATIVE_Y">The <field>Y</field> value is a relative coordinate.</type>
<type name="RELATIVE_RADIUS_X">The <field>RoundX</field> value is a relative coordinate.</type>
<type name="RELATIVE_RADIUS_Y">The <field>RoundY</field> value is a relative coordinate.</type>
</types>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Height</name>
      <comment>The height of the rectangle.  Can be expressed as a fixed or relative coordinate.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
      <description>
<p>The height of the rectangle is defined here as either a fixed or relative value.  Negative values are permitted (this will flip the rectangle on the vertical axis).</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>RoundX</name>
      <comment>Specifies the size of rounded corners on the horizontal axis.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
      <description>
<p>The corners of a rectangle can be rounded by setting the RoundX and RoundY values.  Each value is interpreted as a radius along the relevant axis.  A value of zero (the default) turns off this feature.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>RoundY</name>
      <comment>Specifies the size of rounded corners on the vertical axis.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
      <description>
<p>The corners of a rectangle can be rounded by setting the RoundX and RoundY values.  Each value is interpreted as a radius along the relevant axis.  A value of zero (the default) turns off this feature.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Width</name>
      <comment>The width of the rectangle.  Can be expressed as a fixed or relative coordinate.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
      <description>
<p>The width of the rectangle is defined here as either a fixed or relative value.  Negative values are permitted (this will flip the rectangle on the horizontal axis).</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>X</name>
      <comment>The left-side of the rectangle.  Can be expressed as a fixed or relative coordinate.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
      <description>
<p>The position of the rectangle on the x-axis is defined here as a fixed or relative coordinate.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Y</name>
      <comment>The top of the rectangle.  Can be expressed as a fixed or relative coordinate.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
      <description>
<p>The position of the rectangle on the y-axis is defined here as a fixed or relative coordinate.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

  </fields>
  <structs>
  </structs>
</book>
