<?xml version="1.0"?>

<group name="system">
  <subgroup name="task">
    <event name="created">
      <short>Indicates that a new task has been started.</>
      <description>
        <p>This event is triggered when a Task object starts a new process.  Any processes created outside of the Parasol sandbox will not be captured by this event.</p>
      </>

      <parameters>
        <p>The following structure is passed when this event is triggered:</p>
        <indent><code>typedef struct { EVENTID EventID; OBJECTID TaskID; OBJECTID ProcessID; } evTaskCreated;</code></indent>
        <p>The TaskID reflects the object ID of the task that created the process.  The ProcessID is the identifier that has been assigned to the process by the host system.</p>
      </>
    </event>

    <event name="removed">
      <short>A task has been removed from the system.</>
      <description>
        <p>When a process created by a <class>Task</> object is destroyed, this event will be triggered.  Any processes created outside of the Parasol sandbox will not be captured by this event.</p>
      </>
      <parameters>
        <p>The following structure is passed when this event is triggered:</p>
        <indent><code>typedef struct { EVENTID EventID; OBJECTID TaskID; OBJECTID ProcessID; } evTaskRemoved;</></>
        <p>The TaskID reflects the object ID of the task that was removed.  The ProcessID is the identifier that has been assigned to the process by the host system.</p>
      </>
    </event>
  </>
</>

<group name="display">
  <subgroup name="resolution">
    <event name="change">
      <short>A change has been made to the resolution of a display.</>
    </>
  </>
</>

<group name="power">
  <subgroup name="state">
    <event name="suspending">
      <short>The machine is in the process of being suspended.</>
    </event>
    <event name="resumed">
      <short>The machine has resumed from a suspended state.</>
    </event>
  </subgroup>

  <subgroup name="display">
    <event name="standby">
      <short>A display has been put into standby mode.</>
    </event>
  </subgroup>

  <subgroup name="battery">
    <event name="critical">
      <short>Battery power has been reduced to a critical level.</>
    </event>
    <event name="low">
      <short>Battery power has been reduced to a very low level.</>
    </event>
  </subgroup>

  <subgroup name="cputemp">
    <event name="high">
      <short>The temperature of a CPU has reached a dangerous level.</>
    </event>
    <event name="critical">
      <short>The temperature of a CPU has reached a critical level.</>
    </event>
  </subgroup>

  <subgroup name="screensaver">
    <event name="on">
      <short>The user's screensaver has been turned on.</>
    </event>
    <event name="off">
      <short>The user's screensaver has been turned off.</>
    </event>
  </subgroup>
</group>

<group name="user">
  <subgroup name="status">
    <event name="login">
      <short>The user has successfully logged in to the system.</>
    </event>
    <event name="logout">
      <short>The user has initiated the logout process.</>
    </event>
    <event name="loggedout">
      <short>The user has been logged out of the system completely.</>
    </event>
  </subgroup>
</group>

<group name="filesystem">
  <subgroup name="assign">
    <event name="created">
      <short>A new filesystem assignment has been created.</>
    </event>
    <event name="deleted">
      <short>An existing filesystem assignment has been removed.</>
    </event>
  </subgroup>
</group>

<group name="hardware">
  <subgroup name="drivers">
    <event name="starting">
      <short>The system hardware drivers are being started on bootup.</>
    </event>
    <event name="started">
      <short>All system hardware drivers have completed their startup process on bootup.</>
    </event>
    <event name="closing">
      <short>All system hardware drivers are about to be closed to shutdown the machine.</>
    </event>
  </subgroup>
</group>

<group name="audio">
  <subgroup name="volume">
    <event name="master">
      <short>The master volume level has changed.</>
    </event>
    <event name="linein">
      <short>The line-in volume level has changed.</>
    </event>
    <event name="mic">
      <short>The microphone volume level has changed.</>
    </event>
    <event name="muted">
      <short>All volume levels have been muted.</>
    </event>
    <event name="unmuted">
      <short>All volume levels are no longer muted.</>
    </event>
  </>
</group>

<group name="io">
  <subgroup name="keymap">
    <event name="change">
      <short>The user's keymap has been changed.</>
    </event>
  </>
</group>
