<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="class.xsl"?>

<book>
  <info>
    <name>VectorClip</name>
    <type>class</type>
    <module>Vector</module>
    <comment>Clips are used to define complex clipping regions for vectors.</comment>
    <version>1</version>
    <id>51b1de80</id>
    <idstring>ID_VECTORCLIP</idstring>
    <category>Graphics</category>
    <include>modules/vectorclip.h</include>
    <copyright>Paul Manias © 2010-2022</copyright>
    <description>
<p>The VectorClip defines a clipping path that can be used by other vectors as a mask.  The clipping path is defined by creating Vector shapes that are initialised to the VectorClip as child objects.</p>
<p>Any Vector that defines a path can utilise a VectorClip by referencing it through the Vector's Mask field.</p>
<p>VectorClip objects must always be owned by their relevant <class name="VectorScene">VectorScene</class> or <class name="VectorViewport">VectorViewport</class>.  It is valid for a VectorClip to be shared by multiple vector objects within the same scene.</p></description>
    <source>
      <file path="vectors/">clip.cpp</file>
    </source>
  </info>

  <fields>
    <field>
      <name>Transform</name>
      <comment>Applies a transform to the paths in the clipping mask.</comment>
      <access write="S">Set</access>
      <type>STRING</type>
      <description>
<p>A transform can be applied to the paths in the clipping mask by setting this field with an SVG compliant transform string.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Units</name>
      <comment>Defines the coordinate system for fields X, Y, Width and Height.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>INT</type>
      <description>
<p>The default coordinate system for clip-paths is <code>BOUNDING_BOX</code>, which positions the clipping region against the vector that references it.  The alternative is <code>USERSPACE</code>, which positions the path relative to the current viewport.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

  </fields>
  <structs>
  </structs>
</book>
