<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="class.xsl"?>

<book>
  <info>
    <name>VectorText</name>
    <type>class</type>
    <module>Vector</module>
    <comment>Extends the Vector class with support for generating text.</comment>
    <version>1</version>
    <id>51bb151d</id>
    <idstring>ID_VECTORTEXT</idstring>
    <category>Graphics</category>
    <include>modules/vectortext.h</include>
    <copyright>Paul Manias © 2010-2022</copyright>
    <description>
<p>To create text along a path, set the #Morph field with a reference to any <class name="Vector">Vector</class> object that generates a path.  The following extract illustrates the SVG equivalent of this feature:</p>
<pre>&lt;defs&gt;
  &lt;path id="myTextPath2" d="M75,20 l100,0 l100,30 q0,100 150,100"/&gt;
&lt;/defs&gt;

&lt;text x="10" y="100" stroke="#000000"&gt;
  &lt;textPath xlink:href="#myTextPath2"/&gt;
&lt;/text&gt;
</pre>
<p>Support for bitmap fonts is included.  This feature is implemented by drawing bitmap characters to an internal <class name="VectorImage">VectorImage</class> and then rendering that to the viewport as a rectangular path.  It is recommended that this feature is only used for fast 1:1 rendering without transforms.  The user is otherwise better served through the use of scalable fonts.</p></description>
    <source>
      <file path="vectors/">text.cpp</file>
    </source>
  </info>

  <actions>
  </actions>

  <methods>
    <method>
      <name>DeleteLine</name>
      <comment>Deletes any line number.</comment>
      <prototype>ERROR vtDeleteLine(OBJECTPTR Object, LONG Line)</prototype>
      <input>
        <param type="LONG" name="Line">The line number that you want to delete.  If negative, the last line will be deleted.</param>
      </input>
      <description>
<p>This method deletes lines from a text object.  You only need to specify the line number to have it deleted.  If the line number does not exist, then the call will fail.  The text graphic will be updated as a result of calling this method.</p>
      </description>
      <result>
        <error code="Okay">The line was deleted.</error>
        <error code="Args">The Line value was out of the valid range.</error>
      </result>
    </method>

  </methods>

  <fields>
    <field>
      <name>Align</name>
      <comment>Defines the alignment of the text string.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>INT</type>
      <description>
<p>This field specifies the horizontal alignment of the text string.  The standard alignment flags are supported in the form of <code>ALIGN_LEFT</code>, <code>ALIGN_HORIZONTAL</code> and <code>ALIGN_RIGHT</code>.</p>
<p>In addition, the SVG equivalent values of <code>start</code>, <code>middle</code> and <code>end</code> are supported and map directly to the formerly mentioned align flags.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>CharLimit</name>
      <comment>Limits the total characters allowed in the string.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>INT</type>
      <description>
<p>Set the CharLimit field to limit the number of characters that can appear in the string.  The minimum possible value is 0 for no characters.  If the object is in edit mode then the user will be unable to extend the string beyond the limit.</p>
<p>Note that it is valid for the <field>String</field> length to exceed the limit if set manually.  Only the display of the string characters will be affected by the CharLimit value.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>CursorColumn</name>
      <comment>The current column position of the cursor.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>INT</type>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>CursorRow</name>
      <comment>The current line position of the cursor.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>INT</type>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>DX</name>
      <comment>Adjusts horizontal spacing on a per-character basis.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE []</type>
      <description>
<p>If a single value is provided, it represents the new relative X coordinate for the current text position for rendering the glyphs corresponding to the first character within this element or any of its descendants.  The current text position is shifted along the x-axis of the current user coordinate system by the provided value before the first character's glyphs are rendered.</p>
<p>If a series of values is provided, then the values represent incremental shifts along the x-axis for the current text position before rendering the glyphs corresponding to the first n characters within this element or any of its descendants. Thus, before the glyphs are rendered corresponding to each character, the current text position resulting from drawing the glyphs for the previous character within the current ‘text’ element is shifted along the X axis of the current user coordinate system by length.</p>
<p>If more characters exist than values, then for each of these extra characters: (a) if an ancestor Text object specifies a relative X coordinate for the given character via a <field>DX</field> field, then the current text position is shifted along the x-axis of the current user coordinate system by that amount (nearest ancestor has precedence), else (b) no extra shift along the x-axis occurs.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>DY</name>
      <comment>Adjusts vertical spacing on a per-character basis.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE []</type>
      <description>
<p>This field follows the same rules described in <field>DX</field>.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Face</name>
      <comment>Defines the font face/family to use in rendering the text string.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>STRING</type>
      <description>
<p>The face/family of the desired font for rendering the text is specified here.  It is possible to list multiple fonts in CSV format in case the first-choice font is unavailable.  For instance, <code>Arial,Open Sans</code> would load the Open Sans font if Arial was unavailable.</p>
<p>If none of the listed fonts are available, the default system font will be used.</p>
<p>Please note that referencing bitmap fonts is unsupported and they will be ignored by the font loader.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Focus</name>
      <comment>Refers to the object that will be monitored for user focussing.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>OBJECTID</type>
      <description>
<p>A VectorText object in edit mode will become active when its nearest viewport receives the focus.  Setting the Focus field to a different vector in the scene graph will redirect monitoring to it.</p>
<p>Changing this value post-initialisation has no effect.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Font</name>
      <comment>The primary Font object that is used to source glyphs for the text string.</comment>
      <access read="G">Get</access>
      <type>OBJECTPTR</type>
      <description>
<p>Returns the <class name="Font">Font</class> object that is used for drawing the text.  The object may be queried but must remain unmodified. Any modification by the client that happens to work in the present code release may fail in future releases.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>FontSize</name>
      <comment>Defines the vertical size of the font.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>STRING</type>
      <description>
<p>The FontSize refers to the height of the font from baseline to baseline.  By default, the value corresponds to the current user coordinate system in pixels.  To define the point size, append 'pt' to the number.</p>
<p>If retrieving the font size, the string must be freed by the client when no longer in use.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>FontStyle</name>
      <comment>Determines font styling.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>STRING</type>
      <description>
<p>Unique styles for a font can be selected through the FontStyle field.  Conventional font styles are <code>Bold</code>, <code>Bold Italic</code>, <code>Italic</code> and <code>Regular</code> (the default).  Because TrueType fonts can use any style name that the designer chooses such as <code>Thin</code>, <code>Narrow</code> or <code>Wide</code>, use <function module="Font">GetList</function> for a definitive list of available style names.</p>
<p>Errors are not returned if the style name is invalid or unavailable.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>InlineSize</name>
      <comment>Enables word-wrapping at a fixed area size.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
      <description>
<p>The inline-size property allows one to set the wrapping area to a rectangular shape. The computed value of the property sets the width of the rectangle for horizontal text and the height of the rectangle for vertical text. The other dimension (height for horizontal text, width for vertical text) is of infinite length. A value of zero (the default) disables the creation of a wrapping area.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>LetterSpacing</name>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>LineLimit</name>
      <comment>Restricts the total number of lines allowed in a text object.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>INT</type>
      <description>
<p>Set the LineLimit field to restrict the maximum number of lines permitted in a text object.  It is common to set this field to a value of 1 for input boxes that have a limited amount of space available.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Rotate</name>
      <comment>Applies vertical spacing on a per-character basis.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE []</type>
      <description>
<p>Applies supplemental rotation about the current text position for all of the glyphs in the text string.</p>
<p>If multiple values are provided, then the first number represents the supplemental rotation for the glyphs corresponding to the first character within this element or any of its descendants, the second number represents the supplemental rotation for the glyphs that correspond to the second character, and so on.</p>
<p>If more numbers are provided than there are characters, then the extra numbers will be ignored.</p>
<p>If more characters are provided than numbers, then for each of these extra characters the rotation value specified by the last number must be used.</p>
<p>If the attribute is not specified and if an ancestor 'text' or 'tspan' element specifies a supplemental rotation for a given character via a 'rotate' attribute, then the given supplemental rotation is applied to the given character (nearest ancestor has precedence). If there are more characters than numbers specified in the ancestor's 'rotate' attribute, then for each of these extra characters the rotation value specified by the last number must be used.</p>
<p>This supplemental rotation has no impact on the rules by which current text position is modified as glyphs get rendered and is supplemental to any rotation due to text on a path and to 'glyph-orientation-horizontal' or 'glyph-orientation-vertical'.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>SelectColumn</name>
      <comment>Indicates the column position of a selection's beginning.</comment>
      <access read="G">Get</access>
      <type>INT</type>
      <description>
<p>If the user has selected an area of text, the starting column of that area will be indicated by this field.  If an area has not been selected, the value of the SelectColumn field is undefined.</p>
<p>To check whether or not an area has been selected, test the <code>AREA_SELECTED</code> bit in the #Flags field.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>SelectRow</name>
      <comment>Indicates the line position of a selection's beginning.</comment>
      <access read="G">Get</access>
      <type>INT</type>
      <description>
<p>If the user has selected an area of text, the starting row of that area will be indicated by this field.  If an area has not been selected, the value of the SelectRow field is undefined.</p>
<p>To check whether or not an area has been selected, test the <code>AREA_SELECTED</code> bit in the #Flags field.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>ShapeInside</name>
      <comment>Reference a vector shape to define a content area that enables word-wrapping.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>OBJECTID</type>
      <description>
<p>This property enables word-wrapping in which the text will conform to the path of a <class name="Vector">Vector</class> shape.  Internally this is achieved by rendering the vector path as a mask and then fitting the text within the mask without crossing its boundaries.</p>
<p>This feature is computationally expensive and the use of <field>InlineSize</field> is preferred if the text can be wrapped to a rectangular area.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>ShapeSubtract</name>
      <comment>Excludes a portion of the content area from the wrapping area.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>OBJECTID</type>
      <description>
<p>This property can be used in conjunction with <field>ShapeInside</field> to further restrict the content area that is available for word-wrapping.  It has no effect if <field>ShapeInside</field> is undefined.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Spacing</name>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>StartOffset</name>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>String</name>
      <comment>The string to use for drawing the glyphs is defined here.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>STRING</type>
      <description>
<p>The string for drawing the glyphs is defined here in UTF-8 format.</p>
<p>When retrieving a string that contains return codes, only the first line of text is returned.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>TextFlags</name>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>INT</type>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>TextLength</name>
      <comment>The expected length of the text after all computations have been taken into account.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
      <description>
<p>The purpose of this attribute is to allow exact alignment of the text graphic in the computed result.  If the #Width that is initially computed does not match this value, then the text will be scaled to match the TextLength.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>TextWidth</name>
      <comment>The raw pixel width of the widest line in the @String value..</comment>
      <access read="G">Get</access>
      <type>INT</type>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>TotalLines</name>
      <comment>The total number of lines stored in the object.</comment>
      <access read="G">Get</access>
      <type>INT</type>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Weight</name>
      <comment>Defines the level of boldness in the text.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>INT</type>
      <description>
<p>The weight value determines the level of boldness in the text.  A default value of 400 will render the text in its normal state.  Lower values between 100 to 300 render the text in a light format, while high values in the range of 400 - 900 result in boldness.</p>
<p>Please note that setting the Weight will give it priority over the <field>FontStyle</field> value.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>X</name>
      <comment>The x coordinate of the text.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
      <description>
<p>The x-axis coordinate of the text is specified here as a fixed value.  Relative coordinates are not supported.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

    <field>
      <name>Y</name>
      <comment>The base-line y coordinate of the text.</comment>
      <access read="G" write="S">Get/Set</access>
      <type>DOUBLE</type>
      <description>
<p>The Y-axis coordinate of the text is specified here as a fixed value.  Relative coordinates are not supported.</p>
<p>Unlike other vector shapes, the Y coordinate positions the text from its base line rather than the top of the shape.</p>
      </description>
    </field>

  </fields>
  <structs>
  </structs>
</book>
